### Hugo A. Matilla Gómez

### Senior Android Developer

Address: Islas Filipinas 6, 28220 Majadahonda, Madrid Tel: 0151 45151829

e-mail: <a href="mailto:hugo.matilla@gmail.com">hugo.matilla@gmail.com</a>
Date of Birth: 27/01/1981

Nationality: Spanish web: matgom.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

To be part of the development team and to contribute to with my experience in Android developments, I.T. business and team work. I feel extremely motivated to continue improving my career in Android Applications development.

### **MY PROJECTS**

After almost two years working at Scondoo as main Android Developer and more than one year at SMF, I have been involved in many projects that are now in the Android Play Store. The duration of the developments I have worked on varied from 1 month to more than a year, and were undertaken both as solo projects and in teams. I also have formative experience in Windows Phone, iOS and JavaScript. Some of the Android projects that can be found in the store include: scondoo, HotUkDeals, reBuy, LernCoachies and DHL.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Android Developer scondoo  Berlin. August. 2013 - Present	At scondoo I overtook with agility and speed the code developed by 2 different agencies. This code was in several cases unstructured. Thanks to my experience I improved it with ease, not only in performance but also in design.
	Technical Skills: Android, Java, JSON, Git, JavaScript
Android Developer  HotUKDeals  Berlin. Nov. 2014 – Feb.2015	I worked remotedly with the HotUKDeals team in Canada building the new generic app, where I rapidly aquire the knowledge of the software architecture and the team methodologies to help them increase their development process.
	Technical Skills: Android, Java, Clean Architecture
Android Developer  Smart Mobile Factory  Berlin. May. 2012 – July.2013	My ability to quickly adapt to new concepts has been useful to develop and improve various Android Applications. Obstacles I must regularly overcome include definition changes, new features, improvements and tight deadlines.
,	Technical Skills: Android, Java, JSON, XML, Windows Phone, Parse.
Web App & ETL Developer  Innova-TSN  Madrid. Jan. 2011 - Feb. 2012	I was quickly integrated in different projects, while experiencing new technical tools, supplying ideas and helping to find solutions. Additionally I assumed managerial and technical responsibilities, and regularly shared my expertise in Oracle with my colleagues.
	Technical Skills: Java, JSP, Html, Css, Batch, C#, Oracle, Eclipse.
ETL Developer  AlamoConsulting	I was part of a small team that developed a large scale corporate DataWarehouse, where versatility was a constant challenge.
Madrid. Jul. 2009 - Dec. 2010	Technical Skills: Oracle, SAS, SAS DIS

### **EDUCATION**

## Postgraduate Studies Mobile Development and Services

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia

Madrid. Dec. 2010 - Jul. 2011

# Computer Science Engineering MSc.

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid Madrid. Sep. 1999 - Mar. 2009 Main Subject Areas: Mobile Web and Android

Applications development.

Minor Subject Areas: Mobile technologies, history,

monetization, and IOS development.

Technical Skills: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Java,

Android, Objective-C, IOS.

**Main Subject Areas**: Programming Methodologies, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Architectures,

Minor Subject Areas: Digital Systems, Microcontrollers

Programming.

**Thesis:** Fairness and Market Based Techniques in Wireless Sensor Networks. Grade 1.3 (TU-Berlin).

### **LANGUAGES**

English	TOEFL Score 94. December 2010.
German	B2 Private School.
Spanish	Mother Tongue.

#### I.T. SKILLS

Programming Languages	Fluent: JAVA (Android)  Basic: Kotlin, Swift, JavaScript, C, C++, Python, ADA95, Haskell.
WEB	Fluent: HTML5, CSS3,  Basic: Meteor, Polymer, React, WorPress, Jekyll.
Databases	Fluent: SQLite, SAS, Oracle, Basic: MySQL, MongoDB, Realm.
Operating Systems	Fluent: Windows, Android.  Basic: UNIX, OSX, iOS.
Documentation	Fluent: UML, E-R. Basic: Gantt.
Agile	Fluent: Kanban, Scrum
Version Control Systems	Fluent: Git

#### **FURTHER INFORMATION**

- Erasmus Programme: TU-Berlin 2007-2009
- Tae-Kwon-Do and Muay Thay black belt.
- Mentor at CoderDojo